Loren Glass Interviews Relating to Grove Press
Loren Glass Interviews Relating to Grove Press
2009-2010
Glass, Loren
12 audio files
Interviews of former members of Grove Press, conducted by Loren Glass as part of the research for his book Counter-Culture Colophon: Grove Press, the Evergreen Review and the Incorporation of the Avant-Garde.
4041738
Biographical History
Grove Press was an American alternative book press founded in 1951 by editor and publisher Barney Rossett. It merged with The Atlantic Monthly Press in 1991 and as of 2010 is an imprint of the publisher Grove/Atlantic, Inc. Grove Press was known for its unusual and sometimes controversial publications, including French avant-garde authors Jean Genet and Eugene Ionesco; Beat poets Jack Kerouac, Allen Ginsberg, and William Burroughs; and books deemed obscene at the time, such as unexpurgated editions of Henry Miller's Tropic of Cancer and D. H. Lawrence's Lady Chatterley's Lover.
Loren Glass is an Associate Professor at the University of Iowa, specializing in 19th and 20th century American literature and culture. He has received numerous awards, honors and grants in recognition of his scholarly work. Counter-Culture Colophon is his second book.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Loren Glass Interviews Relating to Grove Press consists of digital audiorecordings of a number of interviews of former members of the avant-garde publishing house Grove Press. The interviews were conducted by Loren Glass as part of the research for his book on the history of the company, entitled Counter-Culture Colophon: Grove Press, the Evergreen Review and the Incorporation of the Avant-Garde (Stanford University Press, 2013).
Interviewees are:
Morgan Entrekin - president and publisher of Grove/Atlantic
Morrie Goldfischer - vice president and director of publicity
Herman Graf - vice president and director of sales
Fred Jordan - vice president and editor of Evergreen Review
Claudia Menza - managing editor and assistant editor of Evergreen Review
Barney Rosset - publisher of Grove Press and Evergreen Review
Judith Schmidt Douw - manager of rights and permissions and foreign rights
Jeanette Seaver - widow of Grove Press editor Richard Seaver
Nat Sobel - vice president and director of sales
Related Material
See also the
Grove Press Records
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Publishing, printing and book arts; Radicalism; Douw, Judith Schmidt.; Entrekin, Morgan.; Glass, Loren.; Goldfischer, Morrie.; Graf, Herman.; Jordan, Fred.; Menza, Claudia.; Rosset, Barney.; Seaver, Jeannette.; Sobel, Nat.; Grove Press.; Book editors -- United States.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Sound recordings.; Interviews.; Authors.; Editors and publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Loren Glass, 2013.
Inventory
- Interviews
  - Entrekin, Morgan, October 26, 2010
  - Goldfischer, Morrie, July 5, 2010
  - Goldfischer, Morrie, October 22, 2010
  - Graf, Herman, October 25, 2010
  - Jordan, Fred, October 6, 2009
  - Jordan, Fred, October 23, 2010
  - Menza, Claudia, October 21, 2010
  - Rosset, Barney, October 5, 2009
  - Rosset, Barney, October 23, 2010
  - Douw, Judith Schmidt, October 9, 2009
  - Seaver, Jeanette, October 21, 2010
  - Sobel, Nat, October 26, 2010